Welcome back to another video editing tutorial using the free software Kdenlive.
欢迎回到使用免费软件Kdenlive的另一个视频编辑教程
In this video, we're going to be adding audio to our video clip and then controlling the volume of that audio.
在这段视频中 我们将在视频剪辑中添加音频 然后控制音频的音量
We'll do fade in, fade out, and I'll show you how to raise and lower the volume of the video at different points in the video.
我们会淡入 淡出 我会向你展示如何在视频中的不同位置提高和降低视频的音量
So to get started, let's pull in.
因此 在开始之前 让我们把车停下来
In fact, I'm going to pull in a video that already has some audio.
事实上 我要放一段已经有一些音频的视频
Am I? No, I don't know if I do. Okay, yeah, I will. So I have this rain runoff, and I also have this audio file.
我是吗 不 我不知道我有没有 好的 我会的 所以我有这个降雨径流 我还有这个音频文件
So this rain is just rain hitting against the window. It's actually the only video clip I have that has some audio with it.
所以这场雨就是雨打在窗户上 这实际上是我唯一有一些音频的视频剪辑
We can play and listen to what this sounds like.
我们可以弹奏和倾听这听起来是什么样子
So if I want to separate out this audio, I can right click and go to split audio. I think we've done this in the past.
因此 如果我想要分离这些音频 我可以右键单击并转到拆分音频 我想我们以前做过这样的事
These are still tied together. If I want them to be untied, I can right click.
这些仍然捆绑在一起 如果我想要解开它们 我可以右击
And go to Ungroup Clips. And now I can move them around independent of each other.
然后转到解组剪辑 现在我可以让它们相互独立地移动
So maybe there's like a loud portion of this thunder. I'm not sure what this is. Let's listen to this.
因此 也许这场雷鸣中有很大一部分是响亮的 我不确定这是什么 让我们来听听这个
So yeah, I can just see, you can see the waveform down there. It gets a little bit louder, a little bit bigger.
所以 是的 我可以看到 你可以看到下面的波形 声音变大了一点 变大了一点
Let's scroll down and look at that. And so let's apply an audio effect to this.
让我们向下滚动 看看这个 因此 让我们将音频效果应用于此
So we go up here to our effects. And we have different audio things we can apply.
所以我们到这里来看看我们的效果 我们有不同的音频设备可以应用
So we can like change the bass, we can do like equalization, add echo, all kinds of different things.
所以我们可以像改变低音 我们可以像均衡 增加回声 各种不同的东西
If you're wanting to change audio though, I would recommend not doing so much of this.
如果你想改变音频 我建议你不要做这么多
And I would recommend using Audacity. Check out some video tutorials on using Audacity.
我建议使用Audacity 查看一些关于使用Audacity的视频教程
So you can actually export this. In fact, if you drag and drop a video file into Audacity,
所以你实际上可以导出这个 事实上 如果您将视频文件拖放到Audacity中
you can import just the audio portion of it, which is pretty cool.
你可以只导入它的音频部分 这是相当酷的
And then you can bring that audio in separately. So I wouldn't worry about most of these.
然后你可以把音频单独带进来 所以我不会担心这些
Most of what you're going to want to do...
你要做的大部分事...
for audio in KdenLive, is just do these audio corrections.
对于KdenLive中的音频 就是做这些音频校正
So you can mute. You can do...
所以你可以静音 你可以...
What I want to show you in this one is doing volume keyframable.
我想在这张图中展示的是音量键帧
So we're going to add this volume over. And what it lets us do
所以我们要把这卷加进去 它让我们做的是
is change the volume based on a certain point.
就是根据某个点改变音量
So we hit this...
所以我们打了这个...
If we go to this first frame, in the last video we kind of learned
如果我们看第一帧 在最后一段视频中
a little bit about animation and keyframes in KdenLive.
关于KdenLive中的动画和关键帧
So if you missed that one, this might be a little bit...
所以如果你错过了这个 这可能有点...
Hard to wrap your head around, but we have these different keyframes.
很难理解 但我们有不同的关键帧
So at a certain point, maybe like this far into the video, at this point,
所以在某个时刻 也许像视频中的这个 在这一点上
we want to click this plus sign and add a keyframe here.
我们要点击这个加号并在这里添加一个关键帧
And then we can change the volume between from this point to this point.
然后我们可以改变从这一点到这一点的体积
We can have the volume fade up, for example.
例如 我们可以把音量调高
So we can have it be very soft.
所以我们可以让它非常柔软
Where's that?
在哪
So we have it start like basically none.
所以我们开始时基本上没有
And then we can have it go louder by the time it gets to this point.
到了这一点我们就可以把声音调大点了
And the cool thing I like about this is we don't have to just control the volume here even though we can.
我喜欢这个的最酷的一点是我们不需要控制音量即使我们可以
But look what's happening down here. We can see these different points.
但看看下面发生了什么 我们可以看到这些不同的点
And so we can actually change the volume and we can move that key frame around just by changing it on here.
所以我们可以改变音量 我们可以移动关键帧 只要改变这里
So we can say get loud here and if we double click on there we can add another key frame in.
所以我们可以在这里说大声点 如果我们双击那里 我们可以添加另一个关键帧
And we can say then get soft here for a little bit.
我们可以说 然后在这里放松一下
And then we can double click and say get really loud right here.
然后我们可以双击然后说大声点
And we can just kind of change the volume of this and then we can be like and by the very
我们可以改变它的音量然后我们就可以
end drop off and be quiet again.
结束了 然后再次安静下来
So what we've done we've set different volumes for different points of this video.
所以我们为这段视频的不同点设置了不同的音量
So now we'll play it and see.
现在我们来播放一下看看
So it starts out kind of soft.
所以刚开始的时候有点软
Really loud.
很大声
And then it gets softer again.
然后又变软了
So that's one way that we can do the volume. There's also some simple things like fade.
所以这是一种方法 我们可以做的体积 还有一些简单的东西 比如褪色
If we just apply a fade in, it'll just do like a fade in on the audio.
如果我们只是应用一个淡出 它只是做一个淡出音频
We can do a fade out on the audio.
我们可以在音频上做一个淡出
But really, the really powerful one is this volume key frameable, which lets you change the volume.
但实际上 真正强大的是这个音量键可帧 它可以让你改变音量
If you have a podcast, for example, you might have some introduction music on your podcast.
例如 如果你有播客 你可能会在播客上有一些介绍音乐
And then you want to lower the volume down while you're talking.
然后你想在你说话的时候把音量调低
Like this. And then towards the end, you raise up the volume again.
这样最后 你再把音量调高
You know, so it might look something like this if you're doing a podcast loud and then soft during the talking and then loud again at the end.
You know, so it might look something like this if you're doing a podcast loud and then soft during the talking and then loud again at 最后
Anyway, that's just kind of what I wanted to show you as far as how to change volume and
总之 这就是我想告诉你的 至于如何改变音量
yeah, adjust sound and music within CadenLive. Go ahead and play with a lot of these though.
是的 在CadenLive中调整声音和音乐 尽管如此 继续玩很多这些
You've got gain. If we delete this, right, we can apply gain and just change the volume like for the whole thing.
你有收获 如果我们删除这个 对 我们可以应用增益 只是改变音量 就像整个事情
From start to finish, it doesn't like fade at all.
从开始到结束 它一点也不喜欢褪色
We can do like, I don't know, normalize audio channels,
我们可以做 我不知道 正常化音频频道
like pan between left and right and different things.
比如左右摇摆和不同的东西
So yeah, play with some of those different audio,
所以 是的 播放一些不同的音频
these audio effects and get familiar with them
熟悉这些音频效果
and it's going to help you create better video projects in the future.
它将帮助你在未来创造更好的视频项目
Thanks for watching. Catch you in the next video.
感谢收看 在下一个视频中看到你